<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aihrif on dayowrites</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/aihrif/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aihrif on dayowrites</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/aihrif/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Confession Not Conformity</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/confession-not-conformity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/confession-not-conformity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&#xA;verse: Daniel 9:1-23&#xA;The church has been on a decline, but it can be reformed. Not by conforming to the world, but by confessing our sins to God. If people want to see a revival of the church, it has to start with every individual member. What does a revived church look like? God&amp;rsquo;s glory is revealed through each individual person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One issue with Korean/Korean-American churches is the over-emphasis of community.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Prosperity Gospel&amp;rdquo; is the theory that as long as you follow Jesus, your life will be easy, fulfilling, prosperous, etc. But the actual teachings of the gospel share a very different idea. The idea that we are all sinners, and that we are condemned to death. But through the grace and death of our Lord Jesus that we are saved.&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of division within the christian church today. People are ignoring the word of God for the sake of cultural acceptance. Some churches are now accepting lgbtq, same sex marriage within the clergy, etc. Furthermore, we have the entertainment focused conservative churches that host intense worships that can be considered concerts. These church services have &amp;ldquo;heightened emotions&amp;rdquo;, but a decline in God&amp;rsquo;s word.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Courageous Consistency</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/courageous-consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/courageous-consistency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 8:27&#xA;Context: This terrible ruler, the king of Greece, was desecrating the church and persecuting the Jews. Daniel had a terrible vision of this that it brought him illness. But even then, we find that in verse 27 that he rose and &amp;ldquo;went about the king&amp;rsquo;s business&amp;rdquo;. He remains &lt;strong&gt;courageously consistent&lt;/strong&gt; although he was facing overwhelming fear and hardship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When life is overwhelming and uncertain, how can we also remain courageously consistent just as Daniel was. Because we can&amp;rsquo;t so this by our own power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resting in the Unknown</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/resting-in-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/resting-in-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 7:15-28&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A man receives a direct vision from God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &amp;lsquo;ancient of days&amp;rsquo; executes judgment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel holds on to the tension of not knowing. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t demand understanding, but instead continues to rest in both the unknown and peace.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People are generally restless with the unknown. We seek answers at every turn. But finding the answer won&amp;rsquo;t result in peace. Often times the answer isn&amp;rsquo;t clear, thus the increase in knowledge leads to confusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Prayer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/persistent-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/persistent-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 6:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;King Darius persian ruler&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel is old now ~80 years old&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People were trying to dig up dirt and find any flaw in his character. The only way to take Daniel down was to attack his devotion to God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;For 30 days, let nobody worship anyone buy you. If you break this law they will be thrown into the Lion&amp;rsquo;s den&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel is being asked to temporarily stop praying for God. Realistically he could reason and say that this is just a small break. But no, he could not compromise this value.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because Daniel disobeyed, he is theown into the lion&amp;rsquo;s den. But even in this dangerous space, he remains calm and continues to pray to God.&#xA;All people have strong grit and resilience. But where are we placing our grit?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;3-facts-about-prayer&#34;&gt;3 Facts about prayer&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer shapes our identity, not just our actions&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notice how Daniel almost &lt;strong&gt;immediately&lt;/strong&gt; goes to pray in his chamber &lt;em&gt;as he&amp;rsquo;s always done&lt;/em&gt;. It was a lifelong practice that was so deeply tied to his identity, rather than it being an action.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a duty to fulfill. Daniel instead builds a deep relationship with God by constantly seeking him out. His being was &lt;strong&gt;shaped&lt;/strong&gt; by his communion with God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How should we handle hardships and stress?&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By not being self-reliant. The more we depend on our weak and human selves, the more we burden ourselves. We need faith instead of fear. This won&amp;rsquo;t come to us unless we center our lives over prayer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a lifelong process of commitment and love of Christ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer is a &lt;strong&gt;lifeline&lt;/strong&gt; not a &lt;strong&gt;last resort&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel didn&amp;rsquo;t pray the moment trouble came. He actually had already been praying consistently before the crisis arrived.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer is more important than life itself. Stop thinking if prayer as a convenience to get what we want. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a religious duty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer is a &lt;strong&gt;lifeline&lt;/strong&gt; built on a &lt;strong&gt;life time&lt;/strong&gt; of discipline. Don&amp;rsquo;t depend on other things because they don&amp;rsquo;t have any value. Have a joyous heart that longs to know God deeply. Only then will you experience a life of persistent prayer and a rise in faith.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What are some good opportunities to pray?&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eating&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Right before going to bed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starting studying&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Before exercise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As you drive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Right as you wake up. Make a time for it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer assures of God&amp;rsquo;s word. It&amp;rsquo;s not an &lt;em&gt;escape&lt;/em&gt; of our troubles&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When Daniel prays &lt;strong&gt;nothing changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He still enters the lion&amp;rsquo;s den. He literally had a HARDER time because he prayed, instead of deliverance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The word of God reveals to us that when we pray, life gets harder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One profound truth of the story: It ends in safety and deliverance. Most importantly the deliverance is applied WITHIN the trial, not pulling Daniel out of the trial. When God could have easily removed troubles from our lives, he instead is right there with us as we go through them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus faced the ultimate punishment for us first, that we would be able to succeed in our small trials.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We can only deal with our current problems so that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to endure with the &lt;strong&gt;ultimate&lt;/strong&gt; problem of eternal suffering. God has not abandoned us. His word came into fulfillment through Jesus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer: Father we thank you in your revalation to us in shwowing us that our communication to you is not just meaning for us to be delivered from our miseries. But rather it&amp;rsquo;s to help us identify ourselves in you and experience your word come true in both our current life and our eternal life. Hello us to see the value of prayer and have greater grit/persistence more than ever befoe rto pray. to count the cost of prayer for your glory and our joy. help us to be anchored in hope and turn to yoy confidently knowing thar Jesus Christ experienced the ultimate death aleeady. Help us to continue rising in faith to obey your word.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vessel of Mercy</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/vessel-of-mercy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/vessel-of-mercy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 5:1-7, 13-31&#xA;Summary: The new King Belshazzar, the successor of King Nebuchadnezzar disrespected God by drinking from the chalices from the temple (the house of God). The feast is reckless because he&amp;rsquo;s chasing dopamine desperately before his death.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;reckless-life-that-speaks-to-humanity&#34;&gt;Reckless life that speaks to humanity&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What does it mean to be reckless?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s to desperately chase something with no avail.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When death is imminent, it is human nature to indulge in sensuality and pleasure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recklessness can be seen in cheating as well. People cheat because they crave and desire something that isn&amp;rsquo;t being found within the relationship.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;revelation-based-on-this-recklessness&#34;&gt;Revelation based on this recklessness&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wisdom can not be found anywhere in the world, only in the word of God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You are a created being by a marvelous creator. You &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to turn to your creator to learn more about them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-need-to-do-as-people-who-are-believing-in-the-word-of-god-our-responsibility&#34;&gt;What we need to do as people who are believing in the word of God, our responsibility.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trust in the word of God. He is the only true source of wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When you reject the word of God, it leads to destruction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In verse 22 it shows that Kiny Belshazzar knew all of the good works of God and his eminence, however he deliberately CHOSE to worship the idols of this world.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are a christian, and truly know the word of God, you need to &lt;strong&gt;abide&lt;/strong&gt; to it. Or else God will judge you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All Christians will be judged but not condemned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To avoid condemnation, we need to believe in the death and resurrection of the Son, Jesus Christ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t get to earn or work for our salvation, but the rewards that we reap in heaven are based upon our trust in him and our works?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God revealed to us his truth, and it is our calling to act on this truth. We need to be vessels of life, not of waste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you think of yourself as a vessel of God and mercy, you will start to act holier. Jesus was the ultimate vessel sacrifice that allows us to be vessels of mercy. If we do this as temples of the holy spirit, we will find signficance and meaning within our lives. Will we ever find satsifcation, meaning, or joy, when you achieve everyrhing for just yourself. You will only be more and more concerned sbout the future. When we act as a vessel of mercy, not only do we find significance in our lives, we start to experience joy. We start to not be shaken by our external circumstances. You will realize the joy thet God has revealed and provided to us really means, because this is how we were designed to be.&#xA;Stay disciplined and firm with the word of God&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Proper Worshipers of God</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/becoming-proper-worshipers-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/becoming-proper-worshipers-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 1:1-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order for us to regain true joy, we must first earnestly strive for the restoration of worship.&#xA;Joy begins with proper worship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can we become proper worshipers of God?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proper worship begins with recognizing the risk of conformity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel and his friends were forced to assimilate into Babylonian culture. They had to adapt to the Babylonian lifestyle, customs, etc. Even new names.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We live in a time of spiritual captivity. We need to recognize and see this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We are surrounded by influences. It could take the shape of a work focused grindset community, or a friend group that makes racist remarks. Culture can so easily be focused on sin. We can&amp;rsquo;t worship God when we induldge in all of these sins and conform to the sinful culture that surrounds you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By recognizing the risk of the influence around us, we can rely on God and make changed to our lives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Basically, the first step to fighting sin is recognizing it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proper risk is about resolving with the righteous decisions&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
