<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Satisfaction on dayowrites</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/satisfaction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Satisfaction on dayowrites</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/satisfaction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three Foundations for a Satisfied Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/three-foundations-for-a-satisfied-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/three-foundations-for-a-satisfied-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;series&#34;&gt;&#xA;  series:&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#series&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;verse-exodus-131-22&#34;&gt;&#xA;  verse: Exodus 13:1-22&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#verse-exodus-131-22&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-idea&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Main Idea:&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#main-idea&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today we will look at spiritual practices that aren&amp;rsquo;t just helpful, but foundational to a joyful and satisfying Christian life. It will shape you to live faithfully and wisefully, even in times of uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Context:&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#context&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Israelites have &lt;strong&gt;finally&lt;/strong&gt; escaped Egypt after the 10 plagues and are beginning their journey through the wildnerness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foundation-1-first-is-for-the-father&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Foundation #1: First is for the Father&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#foundation-1-first-is-for-the-father&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Found in verse 2, God says to mose, &amp;ldquo;Consecrate to me all the firstborn&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. This commandment is saying that the first and foremost is for the &lt;strong&gt;father&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not referring to control, rather prioritizing a relationship with God. Our lives are objectively undeserved. One man suffered a terrible death so that we may live.  Consecrating the first born is a constant reminder of the great act of Jesus to die on the cross for our sins. Note that you cannot serve two masters. Often times we chase after worldly things such as money, sexual validation, etc., but no matter how much of those things we possess, the dopaminergic feeling eventually fades. There&amp;rsquo;s an alarming statistic of younger people giving much less to the church. And through survey, the findings showed that the primary reason behind this is that younger people stopped &lt;em&gt;trusting&lt;/em&gt; that the church would use the donation wisely. But the unfortunate reality behind this lack of trust is that we fail to practice the act of giving faithfully and sactificially. The Bible teaches us that the &lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; we &lt;strong&gt;give&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;strong&gt;more&lt;/strong&gt; we will &lt;strong&gt;receive&lt;/strong&gt; back, whether directly or indirectly. If you&amp;rsquo;re in a spot where you just absolutely cannot trust your Church with your money, please go find a new church and pour yourself out there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Already Enough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/already-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/already-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;series&#34;&gt;&#xA;  series:&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#series&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;verse-exous-121-13&#34;&gt;&#xA;  verse: Exous 12:1-13&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#verse-exous-121-13&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Intro:&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#intro&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Flushing the toilet in albania was mad awkward and ineffective? PJ also had trouble completing assignments because of technical difficulties with the laptop battery. Despite all of these difficult experiences in Albania, it ended up alright. This is because as humans, &lt;strong&gt;we can adjust&lt;/strong&gt;. When PJ moved to the U.S, it felt like Heaven. He felt really blessed, but also &lt;strong&gt;undeserving&lt;/strong&gt; of all this goodness. But the longer he lived in the U.S., the slowly became more desensitized. And this is an analogy for how as Christians, we become desensitized to the grace of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
