<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on dayowrites</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on dayowrites</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My New Perspective on &#34;Min-Maxing&#34; Life.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/new-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so tired of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been chasing success for the good part of the last 4 years, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a genius to see that it&amp;rsquo;s done more harm than good for me. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly unhappy with myself, and I rarely give myself grace when it comes to failing. There&amp;rsquo;s this constant burden to work hard and it&amp;rsquo;s been so suffocating and stressful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a perpetual cycle of greed and dissatisfaction. And it&amp;rsquo;s also done harm to the perception of my own image. I hate the way I look, I&amp;rsquo;ve developed an eating disorder to the point that I force myself to throw up at times. I constantly compare myself to peers and put myself down and harbor envy towards them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Productivity Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/productivity-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/productivity-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;warning-work-in-progress&#34;&gt;&#xA;  warning: Work in progress&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#warning-work-in-progress&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I currently employ a suite of different tools to track:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What I eat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How I spend my time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;m feeling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Exercise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-eat-macrofactor&#34;&gt;&#xA;  What I eat: MacroFactor&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-i-eat-macrofactor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WIP&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-spend-my-time-timelines--ios-shortcuts&#34;&gt;&#xA;  How I spend my time: TimeLines + iOS Shortcuts&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#how-i-spend-my-time-timelines--ios-shortcuts&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-im-feeling-physical-journaling&#34;&gt;&#xA;  How I&amp;rsquo;m feeling: Physical Journaling&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#how-im-feeling-physical-journaling&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exercise-apple-watch--timelines-sync&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Exercise: Apple Watch + TimeLines Sync&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#exercise-apple-watch--timelines-sync&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First blog post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The reason for starting this blog is to get my thoughts down into writing in a medium that I can share. I want to attach this to my personal website and express my ideas with the small hope that it&amp;rsquo;ll resonate with somebody else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop lettings others choose where to eat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/stop-lettings-others-choose-where-to-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/stop-lettings-others-choose-where-to-eat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To go on a little tangent, I used to think that letting other people choose where to eat was the right thing to do. The nice thing to do, because you&amp;rsquo;re letting them choose what they want to eat right? But often times, when people are given the responsibility of choice, they freeze up, they struggle to pick a place because they want to find a place that everyone wants to eat, but are not confident in doing so. This is why I find it so important for there to be someone that is willing to bear the brunt of choosing a place, even if that means being blamed when people are unhappy with the decision. It&amp;rsquo;s better to lift the burden of having to choose away from someone else, and instead take it upon yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking My Health Seriously</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/taking-my-health-seriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/taking-my-health-seriously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s writing is going to be over my goals for the month of December 2024.&#xA;For far too long have I &amp;ldquo;understood&amp;rdquo; the importance of diet, sleep, and exercise to not make an active change in my lifestyle. It is finally time for this 20 year old boy to become a man and live a healthier life. My goals will be stated below for this month of December, and if I can just do this for one month, I&amp;rsquo;ll be locked in for the rest of my life is my assumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Bullshit Guide to Getting Your Life Back Together</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-bullshit-guide-to-getting-your-life-back-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/no-bullshit-guide-to-getting-your-life-back-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zero commentary, just tips.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide is simply a small list of actionable decisions that you can make in your daily life to give your mind a break and your thoughts some clarity. It&amp;rsquo;s done wonders for my productivity and stopped the cycle of self-loathing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Delete all social media and clear out your notifications. Just try it for a week and you&amp;rsquo;ll realize how much you &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; need it. Stop looking at your damn phone so often.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Charge all of your technology on your desk. Keep it away from your bed at all times. When you lay down to sleep, there should be no technology within an arms reach. As a bonus, this will force you to get out of bed when you turn off your alarm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Journal daily. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be an extensive entry. Even a simple &amp;ldquo;highlight of the day&amp;rdquo; along with some habit tracking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stop listening to music. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy addiction to succumb to and it plagues our minds more than we would expect. Our brain is such a beautiful organ, and it enables us to have deep and emotional thoughts. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re having negative or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; thoughts, drowning them out with music will not do you any good. Process your emotions and let your thoughts carry out and finish. This is the healthiest way to be more mindful.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Especially while driving, stop listening to music in the car and just sit with your thoughts and just pay attention to the road.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read books. Literally anything. Find something enjoyable whether it be a fictional mystery, biography, self help book, the bible, and just read. Reading and writing is the most important skill that we have. To let it go to waste is such a shame, and will be one of your most hurtful regrets. Reading is so powerful because of the way that we receive the information. We get to develop a relationship with the author and consume the content in the way they chose to present it. We delay our graitification and require focus and committment to feel the pleasure from a story. This starkly contrasts to the instant gratification of many pleasures of this world such as junk food, pornography, youtube, short-form video content, etc. for a good reason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drink only water. It&amp;rsquo;s God&amp;rsquo;s gift and is the most nourishing for our bodies and soul. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason why we can drink water and go, &amp;ldquo;Yes this is what my body needed&amp;rdquo;, and yet not have that reaction to literally anything else. So keep a large water bottle with you at all times, at least 24 oz but preferably 32 oz.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get enough sleep. You should stop aiming for a certain number of hours, but enough for your body to not wake up tired. Another helpful tip is to set an alarm to &lt;strong&gt;go to bed&lt;/strong&gt;, not to wake up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take vitamins daily. Omega 3, vitamin C, vitamin D, magnesium, biotin, whatever it is that your body needs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep your desk and workspace clean. You feel more productive when your space is cleaned and minimal. Not sure how much research has gone into this but I can speak anecdotally that it&amp;rsquo;s true.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I personally enjoy doing a 10-15 minute stretch every night. 4 deep breaths for every position and hit every major muscle group. Definitely do this if you exercised or sat in a chair for an extended period of time which is more than likely everyday for most of us.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take care of yourself and your appearance. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to shave. Smell good. Maintain a nice hair cut. When you&amp;rsquo;re confident in yourself, you can be confident in what you do. It&amp;rsquo;ll inspire you to do more.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
