<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on dayowrites</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on dayowrites</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Divine Disruption</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/divine-disruption/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/divine-disruption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: The God who remembers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Exodus 3:1-4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Moses is running away after killing an Egyptian worker for mistreating a Hebrew.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In this set of verses, Moses finds an eternally burning bush.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Note that we can easily consider this a miracle, however it is also not so easily observed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-idea&#34;&gt;Main Idea&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are moments when we go to God asking for something we desire or feel like we need. But sometimes God answers us by making life more difficult/troublesome. There are often things that we don&amp;rsquo;t realize need to be addressed until God tells us they need to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Alabaster Flask</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-alabaster-flask/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-alabaster-flask/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: College group&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Mark 14:1-11&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In this verse we find a woman who pours an alabaster flask which is worth a year&amp;rsquo;s wage and dumps it on Jesus. It&amp;rsquo;s an expressive act that emphasizes her love for Jesus Christ. This in juxtoposition to Judas betraying Jesus for mere dollars demonstrates how being faithful to Christ will &lt;em&gt;cost&lt;/em&gt; us in a &lt;em&gt;worldly&lt;/em&gt; sense, and &lt;em&gt;rejecting&lt;/em&gt; God will barely provide benefit to us in the worldy sense.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus was sinless and lived a perfect life. Yet he lives in a sinless broken world, so how can we act accordingly and similarly to him.&#xA;In other words, what does God want from his people?&#xA;Well obviously obedience, but what does that look like?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing as God Sees</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/seeing-as-god-sees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/seeing-as-god-sees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: The God who remembers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Exodus 2:1-10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The story of Moses&amp;rsquo; birth. His mother hid him in the reeds and the Phaoroh&amp;rsquo;s daughter decides to spare his life. She names him Moses because she, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Drew him out of the water&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Admist a chaos for the Israelites, the mother of Moses sees it differently.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Instead of fearing for her child&amp;rsquo;s life, she instead has a vision similar to God&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the mother deems her son as, &amp;ldquo;Fine&amp;rdquo; or in Hebrew, &amp;ldquo;Tov&amp;rdquo;. Which directly translates to &lt;strong&gt;Good&lt;/strong&gt;. This echos the ideas from Genesis 1, where God found things Good. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t about the child&amp;rsquo;s physical appearance. It was about his &lt;em&gt;character&lt;/em&gt; and she found it good.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously as humans, we have a tendency to react things in a worldly manner. But how much more joyful and at peace could we be if we saw things the way God sees it?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Where is God in this?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/where-is-god-in-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/where-is-god-in-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: The God who remembers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Exodus 1:1-22&#xA;&amp;ldquo;You won&amp;rsquo;t find any mention of God, miracles, signs, or any amazing parables. Rather hardship, suffering, oppression. But you will see that God is still deeply in work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-god-silent-sometimes&#34;&gt;Why is God silent sometimes?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To give us hope to something &lt;strong&gt;greater&lt;/strong&gt;. Contextually, the Israelites have experienced an absence of God for roughly 400 years. In verse 1, we see the geneological descendants of Abraham in order to show that God is working on the promises he made back in Genesis. God is always there. And he has a masterful plan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God builds slowly. We see that the people nation of Israel grow to great heights. God has been faithfully helping them multply and grow into a nation. God siliently aided the Israelites.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-god-doing-during-these-lulls&#34;&gt;What is God doing during these lulls?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Silence does not equate to God not working with us. He is always with us and constantly watching over us and working within us. He is always holding our hand. Stand firm and abide in Him.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There will be worldly things that will try to pull you away from trusting in God. They will rip you apart and tear you to pieces. And God &lt;strong&gt;allows these moments too&lt;/strong&gt;. God continues to stay silent but also continues to work. This is because he cares about us and would rather us grow than bring immediate relief. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not punishment, it&amp;rsquo;s preparation for something better&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-should-we-navigate-through-these-quiet-times&#34;&gt;How should we navigate through these quiet times?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Daily faithfulness but what does this look like? Often it&amp;rsquo;ll feel like, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going nowhere. I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough. I&amp;rsquo;m not producing enough. Where are the results?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual Discipline</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/spiritual-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/spiritual-discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series:  Silence and Solitude&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Mark 6:30-32&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world is fast, we prioritize speed and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we don&amp;rsquo;t take time to recognize God and feel his presence, life and time will slip right past you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need moments to absorb and reflect what we&amp;rsquo;re going through in order to avoid the effect of missing what is happening or recognizing what you&amp;rsquo;ve been through.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;christ-calls-to-calm&#34;&gt;Christ calls to calm&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mark 6:30-32&#xA;Take a break. Reset yourself&#xA;Intentionally seek God and retreat. Spend tome with God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waiting Beyond Time</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/waiting-beyond-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/waiting-beyond-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series:  Counter Cultural Convictions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 12:1-13&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[Time Anxiety]]&#xA;But time is a gift.&#xA;Hold firmly to God&amp;rsquo;s sovereignty, trust in his plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need to have the courage to wait beyond time. What does this mean?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-time-so-valuable&#34;&gt;Why is time so valuable?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How we spend our time is how we define our identity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Faster is better&amp;rdquo; is an idea that many people in society identify themselves with. Many of us believe that there is value in speed and efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;[[Time Famine]] is the idea that no matter how hard we try, we &lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;/strong&gt; accomplish everything that we desire.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Time is supposed to be a gift from God to Cherish, but it has devolved into something else.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-waiting-do-to-us-the-benefit&#34;&gt;What does waiting do to us? The benefit?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Waiting shifts our identity into people of &lt;strong&gt;holiness&lt;/strong&gt; rather than &lt;strong&gt;hopelessness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A difficult season of waiting is not accidental. There&amp;rsquo;s a purpose for our trials. &amp;ldquo;Blessed is he who waits&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Periods of waiting allow us to remove impurities and strife.  It strengthens our faith in God. Actively waiting produces holiness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The wicked will respond to waiting with wickedness and strife. But believers who wait on God actively by keeping their faith will be rewarded.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO NOT FEAR&lt;/strong&gt;: your job is not to climb a ladder or sprint in a race. It&amp;rsquo;s to wait for God to let you do as you do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-are-we-to-be-people-that-wait-beyond-time&#34;&gt;How are we to be people that wait beyond time?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Waiting isn&amp;rsquo;t an obstacle, it&amp;rsquo;s not an obstruction. It&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to look forward to and feel excited about because it&amp;rsquo;s a chance for us to show our piety.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember God&amp;rsquo;s providence and promises&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not about the circumstance we find ourselves in. It&amp;rsquo;s about who we are and who is behind us, which is God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God promises us an eternal inheritance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Go All In On God</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/how-to-go-all-in-on-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/how-to-go-all-in-on-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recognize how weak and insignificant you are.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You are not as righteous as you are&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus tells us to &amp;ldquo;take from me&amp;rdquo; his righteousness&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Go to Christ and ask for his help to be righteous&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shake God&amp;rsquo;s hand&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaking hands is a classic greeting that we often use when we invite someone into our home. We need to invite the holy spirit into our hearts, welcome God into our lives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus will come into our lives and will eat with us&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We will share a meal together, a very intimate experience. God doesn&amp;rsquo;t want just a small snack or entree. He wants to spend the entire evening together, all the way to dessert.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Main takeaway&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First blog post</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/first-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/first-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The reason for starting this blog is to get my thoughts down into writing in a medium that I can share. I want to attach this to my personal website and express my ideas with the small hope that it&amp;rsquo;ll resonate with somebody else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop lettings others choose where to eat</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/stop-lettings-others-choose-where-to-eat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/stop-lettings-others-choose-where-to-eat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To go on a little tangent, I used to think that letting other people choose where to eat was the right thing to do. The nice thing to do, because you&amp;rsquo;re letting them choose what they want to eat right? But often times, when people are given the responsibility of choice, they freeze up, they struggle to pick a place because they want to find a place that everyone wants to eat, but are not confident in doing so. This is why I find it so important for there to be someone that is willing to bear the brunt of choosing a place, even if that means being blamed when people are unhappy with the decision. It&amp;rsquo;s better to lift the burden of having to choose away from someone else, and instead take it upon yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Taking My Health Seriously</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/taking-my-health-seriously/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/taking-my-health-seriously/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s writing is going to be over my goals for the month of December 2024.&#xA;For far too long have I &amp;ldquo;understood&amp;rdquo; the importance of diet, sleep, and exercise to not make an active change in my lifestyle. It is finally time for this 20 year old boy to become a man and live a healthier life. My goals will be stated below for this month of December, and if I can just do this for one month, I&amp;rsquo;ll be locked in for the rest of my life is my assumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confession Not Conformity</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/confession-not-conformity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/confession-not-conformity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&#xA;verse: Daniel 9:1-23&#xA;The church has been on a decline, but it can be reformed. Not by conforming to the world, but by confessing our sins to God. If people want to see a revival of the church, it has to start with every individual member. What does a revived church look like? God&amp;rsquo;s glory is revealed through each individual person.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One issue with Korean/Korean-American churches is the over-emphasis of community.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Prosperity Gospel&amp;rdquo; is the theory that as long as you follow Jesus, your life will be easy, fulfilling, prosperous, etc. But the actual teachings of the gospel share a very different idea. The idea that we are all sinners, and that we are condemned to death. But through the grace and death of our Lord Jesus that we are saved.&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of division within the christian church today. People are ignoring the word of God for the sake of cultural acceptance. Some churches are now accepting lgbtq, same sex marriage within the clergy, etc. Furthermore, we have the entertainment focused conservative churches that host intense worships that can be considered concerts. These church services have &amp;ldquo;heightened emotions&amp;rdquo;, but a decline in God&amp;rsquo;s word.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Courageous Consistency</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/courageous-consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/courageous-consistency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 8:27&#xA;Context: This terrible ruler, the king of Greece, was desecrating the church and persecuting the Jews. Daniel had a terrible vision of this that it brought him illness. But even then, we find that in verse 27 that he rose and &amp;ldquo;went about the king&amp;rsquo;s business&amp;rdquo;. He remains &lt;strong&gt;courageously consistent&lt;/strong&gt; although he was facing overwhelming fear and hardship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When life is overwhelming and uncertain, how can we also remain courageously consistent just as Daniel was. Because we can&amp;rsquo;t so this by our own power.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resting in the Unknown</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/resting-in-the-unknown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/resting-in-the-unknown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 7:15-28&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A man receives a direct vision from God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &amp;lsquo;ancient of days&amp;rsquo; executes judgment.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel holds on to the tension of not knowing. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t demand understanding, but instead continues to rest in both the unknown and peace.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People are generally restless with the unknown. We seek answers at every turn. But finding the answer won&amp;rsquo;t result in peace. Often times the answer isn&amp;rsquo;t clear, thus the increase in knowledge leads to confusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Prayer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/persistent-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/persistent-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 6:10&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;King Darius persian ruler&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel is old now ~80 years old&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People were trying to dig up dirt and find any flaw in his character. The only way to take Daniel down was to attack his devotion to God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;For 30 days, let nobody worship anyone buy you. If you break this law they will be thrown into the Lion&amp;rsquo;s den&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel is being asked to temporarily stop praying for God. Realistically he could reason and say that this is just a small break. But no, he could not compromise this value.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Because Daniel disobeyed, he is theown into the lion&amp;rsquo;s den. But even in this dangerous space, he remains calm and continues to pray to God.&#xA;All people have strong grit and resilience. But where are we placing our grit?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;3-facts-about-prayer&#34;&gt;3 Facts about prayer&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer shapes our identity, not just our actions&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notice how Daniel almost &lt;strong&gt;immediately&lt;/strong&gt; goes to pray in his chamber &lt;em&gt;as he&amp;rsquo;s always done&lt;/em&gt;. It was a lifelong practice that was so deeply tied to his identity, rather than it being an action.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a duty to fulfill. Daniel instead builds a deep relationship with God by constantly seeking him out. His being was &lt;strong&gt;shaped&lt;/strong&gt; by his communion with God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How should we handle hardships and stress?&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By not being self-reliant. The more we depend on our weak and human selves, the more we burden ourselves. We need faith instead of fear. This won&amp;rsquo;t come to us unless we center our lives over prayer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a lifelong process of commitment and love of Christ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer is a &lt;strong&gt;lifeline&lt;/strong&gt; not a &lt;strong&gt;last resort&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel didn&amp;rsquo;t pray the moment trouble came. He actually had already been praying consistently before the crisis arrived.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer is more important than life itself. Stop thinking if prayer as a convenience to get what we want. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a religious duty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer is a &lt;strong&gt;lifeline&lt;/strong&gt; built on a &lt;strong&gt;life time&lt;/strong&gt; of discipline. Don&amp;rsquo;t depend on other things because they don&amp;rsquo;t have any value. Have a joyous heart that longs to know God deeply. Only then will you experience a life of persistent prayer and a rise in faith.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What are some good opportunities to pray?&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eating&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Right before going to bed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starting studying&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Before exercise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As you drive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Right as you wake up. Make a time for it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prayer assures of God&amp;rsquo;s word. It&amp;rsquo;s not an &lt;em&gt;escape&lt;/em&gt; of our troubles&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When Daniel prays &lt;strong&gt;nothing changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He still enters the lion&amp;rsquo;s den. He literally had a HARDER time because he prayed, instead of deliverance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The word of God reveals to us that when we pray, life gets harder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One profound truth of the story: It ends in safety and deliverance. Most importantly the deliverance is applied WITHIN the trial, not pulling Daniel out of the trial. When God could have easily removed troubles from our lives, he instead is right there with us as we go through them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jesus faced the ultimate punishment for us first, that we would be able to succeed in our small trials.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We can only deal with our current problems so that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to endure with the &lt;strong&gt;ultimate&lt;/strong&gt; problem of eternal suffering. God has not abandoned us. His word came into fulfillment through Jesus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer: Father we thank you in your revalation to us in shwowing us that our communication to you is not just meaning for us to be delivered from our miseries. But rather it&amp;rsquo;s to help us identify ourselves in you and experience your word come true in both our current life and our eternal life. Hello us to see the value of prayer and have greater grit/persistence more than ever befoe rto pray. to count the cost of prayer for your glory and our joy. help us to be anchored in hope and turn to yoy confidently knowing thar Jesus Christ experienced the ultimate death aleeady. Help us to continue rising in faith to obey your word.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vessel of Mercy</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/vessel-of-mercy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/vessel-of-mercy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 5:1-7, 13-31&#xA;Summary: The new King Belshazzar, the successor of King Nebuchadnezzar disrespected God by drinking from the chalices from the temple (the house of God). The feast is reckless because he&amp;rsquo;s chasing dopamine desperately before his death.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;reckless-life-that-speaks-to-humanity&#34;&gt;Reckless life that speaks to humanity&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What does it mean to be reckless?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s to desperately chase something with no avail.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When death is imminent, it is human nature to indulge in sensuality and pleasure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recklessness can be seen in cheating as well. People cheat because they crave and desire something that isn&amp;rsquo;t being found within the relationship.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;revelation-based-on-this-recklessness&#34;&gt;Revelation based on this recklessness&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wisdom can not be found anywhere in the world, only in the word of God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You are a created being by a marvelous creator. You &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to turn to your creator to learn more about them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-we-need-to-do-as-people-who-are-believing-in-the-word-of-god-our-responsibility&#34;&gt;What we need to do as people who are believing in the word of God, our responsibility.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trust in the word of God. He is the only true source of wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When you reject the word of God, it leads to destruction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In verse 22 it shows that Kiny Belshazzar knew all of the good works of God and his eminence, however he deliberately CHOSE to worship the idols of this world.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are a christian, and truly know the word of God, you need to &lt;strong&gt;abide&lt;/strong&gt; to it. Or else God will judge you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All Christians will be judged but not condemned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To avoid condemnation, we need to believe in the death and resurrection of the Son, Jesus Christ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t get to earn or work for our salvation, but the rewards that we reap in heaven are based upon our trust in him and our works?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God revealed to us his truth, and it is our calling to act on this truth. We need to be vessels of life, not of waste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you think of yourself as a vessel of God and mercy, you will start to act holier. Jesus was the ultimate vessel sacrifice that allows us to be vessels of mercy. If we do this as temples of the holy spirit, we will find signficance and meaning within our lives. Will we ever find satsifcation, meaning, or joy, when you achieve everyrhing for just yourself. You will only be more and more concerned sbout the future. When we act as a vessel of mercy, not only do we find significance in our lives, we start to experience joy. We start to not be shaken by our external circumstances. You will realize the joy thet God has revealed and provided to us really means, because this is how we were designed to be.&#xA;Stay disciplined and firm with the word of God&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiritual Meekness</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/spiritual-meekness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/spiritual-meekness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Matthew 5:5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to be meek?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Biblical definition: Not weakness, but strength under control. Submissive but strong.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Easily imposed on&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Humble, slow to anger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meekness is a difficult quality to achieve.&#xA;Itâ€™s similar to stoicism. Not defensive or confrontational.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;you need to find your satisfaction in being a child of God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You are already meek or capable of it as a person that has accepted Jesus has your Lord and Savior.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Courage to Lose Control</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/courage-to-lose-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/courage-to-lose-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Counter cultural convictions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 4:28-37&#xA;King Nebuchadnezzar is humiliated and humbled because he was so prideful. Not just a boastful nature, but a &lt;strong&gt;spiritual pride&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do we have spiritual pride?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spiritual pride leaves to an obsession with control. Nebechadnezzar thinks that the fruits of his labor all came by his own doing. Spiritual restoration occured when he let go of his control and gave all glory to God most high.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faithful in the Fire</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/faithful-in-the-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/faithful-in-the-fire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Steadfast faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 3&#xA;Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego are cast into the fire for not worshipping Nevuchadnezzar&amp;rsquo;s idol. They survive through the power of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are human. We have fears of failure and an expectation of loss. We all live in &lt;strong&gt;fire&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Main idea: So how can we hold on to our convictions without being consumed by the fire.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pluralism: What we think about the &lt;strong&gt;most&lt;/strong&gt; is our god. It becomes our greatest concern.&#xA;When does suffering consume us&#xA;When we stop focusing our time and attention on God&#xA;How does God deliver us in those moments.&#xA;By encountering Him. Recognize his presence and in his divine protection. He will be WITH us through hard moments rather than removing them. And this is because our God is relational, not a wish maker. He cares and loves us and relates with us. A personal encounter with God in these hard times affirms our love and faithfulness with God.&#xA;What do we do to hold on to these convictions.&#xA;Focus on the &amp;ldquo;fourth man&amp;rdquo; and not on the fire/heat. Be confident and focused on God.&#xA;Recognize that God&amp;rsquo;s suffering was our means for salvation&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Straying Away From Idolatry</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/straying-away-from-idolatry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/straying-away-from-idolatry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Pastor Myung&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Exodus 32:1 The golden calf idol&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There must only be God in our hearts when we desire to worship the Lord. There shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be any ulterior motive or something that takes precedence such as friends or the pastor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The israelites struggled with faith in the Lord because they couldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; him. While Moses was gone, they couldn&amp;rsquo;t bear to patiently wait and instead created their own God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Wisdom of God</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-wisdom-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-wisdom-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Counter Cultural Convictions&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We need to recognize that we are NEVER in control of our lives, no matter how much we want to believe otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where do we place our trust in today? Ourselves, our pride?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s insight for the &lt;em&gt;best&lt;/em&gt; way to live.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The book of Daniel shows this when God reveals the mystery when no person of flesh could.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We need to discernment and insight into how God is working in our lives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recognize that GOD is in control &lt;strong&gt;not us&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is our response to times of need?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It should be God and his godly wisdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do we need wisdom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming Proper Worshipers of God</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/becoming-proper-worshipers-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/becoming-proper-worshipers-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Anchored in hope, rising in faith&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Daniel 1:1-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In order for us to regain true joy, we must first earnestly strive for the restoration of worship.&#xA;Joy begins with proper worship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can we become proper worshipers of God?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proper worship begins with recognizing the risk of conformity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Daniel and his friends were forced to assimilate into Babylonian culture. They had to adapt to the Babylonian lifestyle, customs, etc. Even new names.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We live in a time of spiritual captivity. We need to recognize and see this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We are surrounded by influences. It could take the shape of a work focused grindset community, or a friend group that makes racist remarks. Culture can so easily be focused on sin. We can&amp;rsquo;t worship God when we induldge in all of these sins and conform to the sinful culture that surrounds you.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By recognizing the risk of the influence around us, we can rely on God and make changed to our lives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Basically, the first step to fighting sin is recognizing it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proper risk is about resolving with the righteous decisions&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Meaning of Christmas</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-meaning-of-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-meaning-of-christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Pastor Myung&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Luke 1:26-56&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The meaning of christmas:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The day that God showed us mercy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A day that God showed his faithfulness&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An important detail to recognize:&#xA;Mary was afraid and felt inferior. But God empowered her saying that she is a child of God and to stand firm on your two feet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more context at this time for Israelites. They have been enslaved for generations. Egypt, assyria, Babylon, and now Rome. They were always proud and were persistent in their faith that everything will be okay. But Rome was an iron fist and people had some doubt over their situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Peace</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/christmas-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/christmas-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Psalm 126&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The true meaning of Christmas is the gift of Jesus Christ and his birth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Out greatest gift and dream is the eternal life that the one and only Jesus Christ died to grant. And this dream has &lt;strong&gt;already&lt;/strong&gt; been actualized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treasure the Word</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/treasure-the-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/treasure-the-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Psalm 119&#xA;the longest verse in the bible. It&amp;rsquo;s the written account of David and his devout faith.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People want to make the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; choice for themselves such as &amp;ldquo;what should we eat?&amp;rdquo;. But this created stress in our lives. But what&amp;rsquo;s a decision that we can &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; forget. It brings joy, peace, stability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Find delight in the word&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dedictate your life to the word&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Look to the hopeful future and be present in the loment.&#xA;Bottom line is to treasure the word of God.&#xA;How can you treasure God when yoy don&amp;rsquo;t treasure the word? Treasuring the word, following the commandments, will help you to make the right decisions and run away from sin.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s societal climate makes reading in general, and also specifically the bible, a great struggle. We are so immersed in a culture of instant gratification. I really have to immerse myself in the word of God and absorb and be mindful of it. This is where we should derive our joy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Praying Our Envy</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/praying-our-envy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/praying-our-envy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Psalm 73&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are you happy for others that do well for themselves or are you envious?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The heart of jealousy happens very often.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get caught up in focusing on what you lack. Instead look towards what you do have.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Envy is difficult to self actualize. We do it so often and we can become complacent to the feeling. As we get more discontent with ourselves, we become greedy, self pitying, and hyper critical of oneself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Brokenness to Beauty</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/from-brokenness-to-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/from-brokenness-to-beauty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Psalm 51&#xA;Writer: King David&#xA;Context: David was considered a man of God&amp;rsquo;s heart and poweful and wealthy. Considered a very righteous man. But he fell, he commited adultery with a married woman. Nathan a prophet convicts King David about his sin. The story of a rich man and a poor man who had just a single lamb that he cherished very much.&#xA;Verse Analysis: The entire verse is a psalm of repentance.&#xA;Three pleas:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Bullshit Guide to Getting Your Life Back Together</title>
      <link>https://example.org/posts/no-bullshit-guide-to-getting-your-life-back-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/posts/no-bullshit-guide-to-getting-your-life-back-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zero commentary, just tips.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide is simply a small list of actionable decisions that you can make in your daily life to give your mind a break and your thoughts some clarity. It&amp;rsquo;s done wonders for my productivity and stopped the cycle of self-loathing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Delete all social media and clear out your notifications. Just try it for a week and you&amp;rsquo;ll realize how much you &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong&gt; need it. Stop looking at your damn phone so often.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Charge all of your technology on your desk. Keep it away from your bed at all times. When you lay down to sleep, there should be no technology within an arms reach. As a bonus, this will force you to get out of bed when you turn off your alarm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Journal daily. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be an extensive entry. Even a simple &amp;ldquo;highlight of the day&amp;rdquo; along with some habit tracking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stop listening to music. It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively easy addiction to succumb to and it plagues our minds more than we would expect. Our brain is such a beautiful organ, and it enables us to have deep and emotional thoughts. Even if you&amp;rsquo;re having negative or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; thoughts, drowning them out with music will not do you any good. Process your emotions and let your thoughts carry out and finish. This is the healthiest way to be more mindful.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Especially while driving, stop listening to music in the car and just sit with your thoughts and just pay attention to the road.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read books. Literally anything. Find something enjoyable whether it be a fictional mystery, biography, self help book, the bible, and just read. Reading and writing is the most important skill that we have. To let it go to waste is such a shame, and will be one of your most hurtful regrets. Reading is so powerful because of the way that we receive the information. We get to develop a relationship with the author and consume the content in the way they chose to present it. We delay our graitification and require focus and committment to feel the pleasure from a story. This starkly contrasts to the instant gratification of many pleasures of this world such as junk food, pornography, youtube, short-form video content, etc. for a good reason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Drink only water. It&amp;rsquo;s God&amp;rsquo;s gift and is the most nourishing for our bodies and soul. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason why we can drink water and go, &amp;ldquo;Yes this is what my body needed&amp;rdquo;, and yet not have that reaction to literally anything else. So keep a large water bottle with you at all times, at least 24 oz but preferably 32 oz.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Get enough sleep. You should stop aiming for a certain number of hours, but enough for your body to not wake up tired. Another helpful tip is to set an alarm to &lt;strong&gt;go to bed&lt;/strong&gt;, not to wake up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take vitamins daily. Omega 3, vitamin C, vitamin D, magnesium, biotin, whatever it is that your body needs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep your desk and workspace clean. You feel more productive when your space is cleaned and minimal. Not sure how much research has gone into this but I can speak anecdotally that it&amp;rsquo;s true.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I personally enjoy doing a 10-15 minute stretch every night. 4 deep breaths for every position and hit every major muscle group. Definitely do this if you exercised or sat in a chair for an extended period of time which is more than likely everyday for most of us.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take care of yourself and your appearance. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to shave. Smell good. Maintain a nice hair cut. When you&amp;rsquo;re confident in yourself, you can be confident in what you do. It&amp;rsquo;ll inspire you to do more.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security in Suffering</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/security-in-suffering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/security-in-suffering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Psalm for Suffering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Psalms 16&#xA;David calls out to God for refuge because he has been experiencing and dealing with various problems such as being a murderer and adulterer, and also bc of the sins of others such as those that seek to end his life. But note that David isn&amp;rsquo;t asking for an tagimmediate solution. Not a refuge in the sense of freedom of his problems, rather a security amidst danger. A refuge/security that cannot be shaken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Praying through Fear</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/praying-through-fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/praying-through-fear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Psalm 3&#xA;Context: David is old and he&amp;rsquo;s being chased by thousands of people. His life is crumbling around him. King David commited adultery and murdered her husband and did a lot of other wrongs.&#xA;Fear is not a negative emotion by itself. It can have positive effects.&#xA;In 1884, Soren Keurtigard says, &amp;ldquo;fear is the response to a specific identifiable danger or threat&amp;rdquo;. Fear of failure, fear of an angry bear&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Soil Parable</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-soil-parable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-soil-parable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024-10-11&#xA;series: college group&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Mark 4:1-34&#xA;Parable of the 4 seeds. Jesus preaching to a big group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus is trying to teach his disciples: &amp;ldquo;The sower sows the Word&amp;rdquo;. The truth be spread and shared to many people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are all types of soil, one of four&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hear the truth but it has zero impact on them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rocky Soil - hear it but doesnt receive it&#xA;Thorns - getting distracted with other desires and things.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XX&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;XX&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Call to Prayer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/a-call-to-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/a-call-to-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 5:13-20&#xA;Pray for one another. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to ask for prayer in times of need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer has the power to change lives. If anyone is suffering in any capacity, let that man pray.&#xA;Are there differences in who prays for us?&#xA;The prayer of a &lt;strong&gt;righteous&lt;/strong&gt; person has a great impact. &amp;ldquo;Is anyone among you sick, so sick that the body the church cannot pray for you. Call for the elders, the leaders of the church, to come pray for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patience</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 5:7-12&#xA;Be patient. Some of you may not be wealthy, maybe suffering, maybe oppressed. But god is exhorting them to be patient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We seek immediate gratification. We are products impatient&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patience -&amp;gt; graciousness and steadiness at the face of delayed gratifications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patience can also mean: Long suffering and remaining steadfast and endure and presevere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not stoicism. It&amp;rsquo;s not about willpower to withstand irritation. It&amp;rsquo;s deeper and more than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Danger of Wealth</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-danger-of-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-danger-of-wealth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 5:1-6&#xA;Your riches will spoil and your coins will corrode. You kept your own pockets fat at the expense of those that work for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who is James condemning?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;James is addressing to a particular group of people: Christians. He&amp;rsquo;s talking about a majority of people in the church.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The issue is the abuse of wealth. Hoarding it instead of using it for the glory of God. Hoarding is different than saving.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Saving is encouraged by the Bible. It makes good stewards. Hoarding is accumulating so much wealth, more than necessary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Are you trying to accumulate wealth so that you can have control over your life? Trust in God, not in wealth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are the dangers of wealth?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cure for Worries</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-cure-for-worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-cure-for-worries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 4:13-17&#xA;Do not be arrogant. Don&amp;rsquo;t boast about tomorrow. Don&amp;rsquo;t talk about doing this or that, just do it. Whatever God wills you to do, just take action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We often become so worried and stressed when things don&amp;rsquo;t go as we plan. How can we deal with this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What causes worries?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forgetting God in our daily lives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Planning without God in mind. The most prevalent and common sin. Whne we forget God in the daily operation of our life, we assume the role of God in ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know whats going to happent tomorrow&amp;rdquo;. This leads to an expectation of a certain reality that may not come true.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WE DONT KNOW WHAT TOMORROW WILL BRING.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leave it all in the hands of God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When plans go well we feel superior, and when they dont we feel inferior.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the cure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Community of Peace part 2</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 4:1-12&#xA;How to build gospel centered communities.&#xA;Last week we learned we need wisdom, especially to deal with conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We all desire change, to be better.&#xA;We want to be people that are reliable and can make a positive impact.&#xA;You get to experience this change, only when you become a peacemaker. When you live in close community with other christians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem of communities:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Community of Peace</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 3:13-18&#xA;Peace makes peace&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is wisdom&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fearing the Lord&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;According to verse 13, Wisdom is not just known, but is shown. &amp;ldquo;Let him show his works in the meekness of wisdom.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wisdom is Pure - Morally blameless&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peaceable - people who dislike conflict. Put reconciliation into action. Means to work with others even though it&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gentleness - As you hear good arguments, that you are willing to change. Flexible, yielding to others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open to reason - Persuadable, a good listener&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Full of mercy - Taking your resources and putting it to use for others in need.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Impartial - Show dignity and respect to all people, because we are all created in the image of God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sincere - Integrity, be wise in public and in private.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We must show these things if you want to be wise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When we are wise, people will come to you, they will be drawn to these characteristics.&#xA;How can we implement it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we don&amp;rsquo;t feel satisfied, we are constantly looking for something to make us feel content.&#xA;Our life feels unsettled and dissatisfied&#xA;This will lead to all kinds of evil and addictions. We find ourseleves doing things we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so that we can be &amp;ldquo;content&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stop Weaponizing your Tongue</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/stop-weaponizing-your-tongue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/stop-weaponizing-your-tongue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 3:1-12&#xA;Importance of words and our tongue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Words are incredibly powerful and have a life long lasting impact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No matter how good a person might be, our natural tendency is to speak evil than good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why are words so powerful?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Verse 6&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Words penetrate both the hearer and the speaker.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Words can destroy a life because of its lasting impact.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When someone curses someone, their words will sometimes turn into action.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WORDS are ACTIONS&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When people bless you with their tongues, they often also bless you with their actions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What do words reveal about ourselves?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>software engineering</title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/notes/university-notes/software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/notes/university-notes/software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-software-engineering-820&#34;&gt;Modern Software Engineering (8/20)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is the point of software engineering? What does it fix?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The problem with software development in the past:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Late&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Too expensive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Poor quality&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And less functional than promised.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The internet was first born in the early 1970s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mid 1990s, the web came ot be.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-software-engineering-822&#34;&gt;Modern Software Engineering (8/22)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Waterfall life cycle model is evil, much worse than agile methodology.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It was the method used for centuries before technology existed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is the fundamental problem with building projects?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Poor project management&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not use good engineering practices.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Example: waterfall methodology&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The waterfall methodology is popular, but this life cycle model doesn&amp;rsquo;t work because of one key issue, that the requirements KEEP CHANGING. Waterfall assumes that the requirements don&amp;rsquo;t change.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;project efficiency - described as a project being on time and within budget.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A low failure rate of software projects is not a direct indication of success or product quality.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If only 1% of projects fail, it may indicate that not enough risks are being taken.&#xA;Multicore is usually better for performance, but there are edge cases where this is not the case.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In situations like these, it&amp;rsquo;s better to go back to singlecore and use rate monotonic analysis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be careful with the decisions you make especially when trying to prioritize speed.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is not worth it to deliver poor quality work at the price of speed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-random-shit-827&#34;&gt;Some random shit (8/27)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-is-devops&#34;&gt;What is devops&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Getting the users involved with the developer team to find what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;how-to-avoid-the-typical-mistakes&#34;&gt;How to avoid the typical mistakes:&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identify problems that have occured in previous projects that have a similar goal to your project.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Discuss major mistakes that were made with other people, whether coworkers in different departments, or even friends in the industry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a checklist of mistakes to be mindful of. Hopefully they don&amp;rsquo;t get checked off&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a list of mistakes to AVOID during planning and monitor cautiously.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a watchdog, an alarm so to speak, to sound whenever your proect starts leaning toward a mistake.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;essential-vs-accidental-complexity&#34;&gt;Essential vs Accidental Complexity&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Any project has a certain aspect of essential complexity, it is just intrinsic to the stuff that we do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>database</title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/notes/university-notes/database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/notes/university-notes/database/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1-databases-and-database-users-08-21&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: Databases and Database Users 08-21&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;vocabulary&#34;&gt;Vocabulary:&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universe of discourse (mini-world)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database management system&lt;/strong&gt; - This software system will do 4 things with the data. Some examples inclued: mySQL, mongoDB, oracle&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Define - Know what information you want to store. Know the data types, the structures and also constraints.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Construct - Populate the database with information.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Manipulate - Performing some kind of query on the table to get a result. This could also include changing information and storing it again.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Retreival, modification, accessing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Share&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database system&lt;/strong&gt; - The entire db system is simply the DMBS + data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;database-types-and-applications&#34;&gt;Database types and applications&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are various data types that a database can store.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the past it was strictly numbers and strings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;But now we can store videos, images.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some applications include:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A geographic info system&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For a database to be useable, we need three things:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mini-world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data is correlated, and what data do we need to show for the user.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identify for WHOM we are storing the data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catalog&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stores the description of a particular databse, e.g. data structures, types, and constraints&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also known as meta-data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-mini-world-exercise&#34;&gt;Example mini-world exercise:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Online car resale database:&#xA;MODELs are of CAR BRANDs&#xA;MODELs have YEARs&#xA;CAR_ID have MODEL and YEARs and AVAILIBILITY&#xA;CAR_SELLERs sell CAR BRANDs&#xA;PEOPLE buy CAR_IDs&#xA;PEOPLE are interested in CAR_IDS&#xA;PEOPLE have SALARYs&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>paradigms</title>
      <link>https://example.org/docs/notes/university-notes/paradigms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/docs/notes/university-notes/paradigms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-preliminaries-819&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: Preliminaries (8/19)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The significant difference between &lt;em&gt;natural&lt;/em&gt; language and &lt;em&gt;programmming&lt;/em&gt; language is &lt;strong&gt;ambiguity&lt;/strong&gt;. Natural language has developed over time, and was not constructed by a team of engineers. Programming languages on the other hand were purposefully created to have unamibguous grammar, whereas english has ambiguous grammar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;English is SVO typology. subject-verb-object&#xA;Starwars Yoda typology: object-subject-verb&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-is-the-effect-of-one-language-being-ambiguous-and-the-other-being-unambiguous&#34;&gt;What is the effect of one language being ambiguous, and the other being unambiguous?&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is no set phonology of a programming language. This conversion from unambiguous grammar into ambiguous grammar, such as from code to english, leads to a possible misinterpretation of meaning (semantics).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Example: Siri still struggles today with pronunciation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;language---set-of-strings-sentences-and-statements&#34;&gt;Language - Set of strings, sentences, and statements&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;English is recursively enumerable. It is possible to list every combination of sentences, but this list would be infinitely long because there is no upper bound, however this does mean that they are &amp;ldquo;countable&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Countable -&amp;gt; They map one to one (onto) each integer of the number system.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are some languages that are infinitely long, but also not countable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turing complete or recursively enumerable?&lt;/strong&gt; How can we realistically find the maximum length of a &amp;lsquo;valid&amp;rsquo; sentence?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We could use grammar rules to define how sentences should be formed. Some of these rules include: syntax, semantics, and grammar.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Syntax allows us to create order when structuring sentences.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Semantics give sentences and words meaning and sense depending on context.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;culture&#34;&gt;Culture&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;every language has some sense of &lt;strong&gt;culture&lt;/strong&gt; of people who are using those languages because they have experience and context. It takes time to adapt to these cultures, but they are not aways intuitive.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;So although things may be allowed, it may not be encouraged.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;why-are-there-so-many-languages&#34;&gt;Why are there so many languages?&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We create new languages based on a need or desire: to solve a specific problem.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If we put all the functionality of every language into a single language, it would be so bloated that it could not be efficient.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;infinity-ordinal-number-theory&#34;&gt;Infinity, Ordinal Number Theory&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are variations of infinity. Infinity is a concept, not a number.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aleph null is an example of this, the cardinality of all natural numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s considered to be the smallest of the infinite symbols.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;linguistics&#34;&gt;Linguistics&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LOGLAN was created to have unambiguous grammar, but still have meaning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis: Language can shape how we perceive and interpret the world.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;p-vs-np&#34;&gt;P vs NP&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Polynomial Time vs Super Polynomial (nonpolynomial) Time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The time it takes to interpret a particular language or sentence takes longer than O(n^k)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;preliminaries-cont-821&#34;&gt;Preliminaries Cont. (8/21)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;first-programming-language&#34;&gt;First Programming Language&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ada Lovelace Bernouli sequence rational thingy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The program was tabular, it didn&amp;rsquo;t go line by line from top to bottom, but could specify where to go after a line was ran.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;first-high-level-programming-language&#34;&gt;First High-level Programming Language&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Plankalkul designed by Konrad Zuze in Germany between 1942 and 1945&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Its original implementation was tabular, but in 1990, the first linear notation was developed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Although it was developed in the 1940s, this code already had&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;floating point arithmetic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;arrays&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;and more&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;files&#34;&gt;Files&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an abstract concept of a container.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The way a file is stored on a disc is continuous and not a single entity.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On computers, files are stored in blocks as a sector. We consider code in a single sector as a page.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A single block or page size is 4096 bytes or 2^12 bytes. In hexadecimal, this is &amp;lsquo;h1000&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How does a disk work?&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A page, or sector, or block in memory is always 4096 bytes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When we create a text file, it will immediately use 1 page worth of memory. Once the content takes up more than the limit, it will retrieve another page worth of memory to store this file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;parse - The term we use to see if a compiler can make sense of the source code.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The file type is important for a compiler.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The extension of a file can be used solely for the use of naming, and not changing the content at all.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For example, a .java file and a .py file are both plain text files. You can compile with either compiler and get the same output so long as its the same source code, and each compiler can make sense of the content.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;However, sometimes a file type could be INCOMPATIBLE with compilers such as .docx or .rtf&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This is because the content is not just plain ascii, but would instead contain formatting that would be extra information that the compiler doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to make sense of it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;source-code-files&#34;&gt;Source Code Files&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These files are purposed for a specific language, and this is identified by the extension.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ex: .py, .java, .pl,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Integrated Development Environment:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An IDE helps us program more efficiently by giving us color highlighting of certain key words, strings, variables, and data types.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An IDE can come in the simple form like notepad++, or get more complicated such as with vsCode&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;esoteric-languages&#34;&gt;Esoteric Languages&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also known as joke languages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many were created for research purposes and to test certain hypothesis, but none of them were created for the purpose of serious use.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whitespace&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This language understands and compiles whitespace characters such as tab, new lines, and spaces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The consequence of the creation of this program was the realization that a single program, a single source code can be interpreted in two vastly different ways by compilers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thus it became very possible to hide information, which is the concept known as steganography.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Branflake&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This language was created for the purpose of being the smallest turing complete language.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It has no variables, only 8 characters that are individual scripts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-3-syntax-and-semantics-826&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: Syntax and Semantics (8/26)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;vocabulary&#34;&gt;Vocabulary:&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Syntax - The structure of expressions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Semantics - The meaning of the expressions and program units&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sentence - string of characters of some alphabet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Language - set of sentences&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can be recursively enumerable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lexeme - (Coloquoially we use &amp;lsquo;word&amp;rsquo;). Refers to the lowest level of syntactic unit such as a word, a variable, punctuation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tokens - Category of its lexemes.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some token can have multiple lexemes, and in other cases it&amp;rsquo;s one to one&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ex: int_literal, identifier are tokens that can refer to multiple lexemes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ex: mult_op, equal_sign are tokens that only refer to a single lexeme.&#xA;![[Pasted image 20240826104425.png]]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;language-recognizers&#34;&gt;Language Recognizers&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generator&lt;/strong&gt; - Device that we can use to generate sentences of a language.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is effectvive because we can compare a sentence syntacically to the generated structure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recognizer&lt;/strong&gt; - Device that checks every alphabetic character of a sentence and verifies if it exists in the alphabet or not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;how-can-we-describe-syntax-effectively&#34;&gt;How can we describe syntax effectively?&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We can use grammars, which are used to describe the syntax of programming language.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;context-free-grammars&#34;&gt;Context-Free Grammars&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A class of grammar used to describe the syntax of &lt;strong&gt;programming&lt;/strong&gt; languages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The reason why it&amp;rsquo;s called context-free because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what the context is.&#xA;$$G=(S, N, T, P)  $$&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;G - Grammar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;S - Start Symbol&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;N - Set of Non-Terminal symbols (tokens)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;T - Set of Terminal Symbols (lexemes)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;P - Set of production rules&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;backus-naur-form&#34;&gt;Backus-Naur Form&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A subset of Context-Free grammar rules.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optimized for describing programming languages. Syntax description&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remember, we want programmign languages to be as unamibguous as possible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;ambiguous-language-is-defined-by-distinct-parse-trees&#34;&gt;Ambiguous language is defined by distinct parse trees.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If a grammar is unambiguous, the derived parse trees should be isomorphic. They have the same nodes and edges, but they may be visually different.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ambiguous language is not inherently bad, so long as we can prove that we can end up at the same result.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ex: 2 + 2 + 4 = &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; + 4 = 8 OR 2 + 2 + 4 = 2 + &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;/strong&gt; = 8&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;derivation&#34;&gt;Derivation&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sequence of repeated application of grammar rules.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reverse derivation: Start with the symbols, and replace them with non-terminal symbols going right to left.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can do the right-most derivation or left-most derivation.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;So long as the graphs are both isomorphic (same leaves and edges), they are unambiguous.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A left-most derivation is like going down a binary tree in preorder.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We expand the left most until we can&amp;rsquo;t, and then we go back up and then down right, until we reach the root node. Once we are back to the top, that is when we begin expanding the right side.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The deeper a procedure is in a parse tree, the closer it is to the leaves, gives it higher precedence. That value must first be evaluated before it can be used in another context.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;functional-languages&#34;&gt;Functional Languages&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We place names on immutable objects instead of some variable shit bro i don&amp;rsquo;t know. Search up the difference ebtween imperative (procedural) languages and functional languages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A DFS will traverse an infinite depth for a recursively enumerable language. So we must use one variation of BFS whether it be post or inorder traversal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can we have faithful works</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/how-can-we-have-faithful-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/how-can-we-have-faithful-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 2:18-26&#xA;Faith without works is dead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God calls us to be a community of love. And this can be achieved even with a group of people that share no interest or have similarities. All we need is God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two pitfalls&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians not doing good works.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians that do good deeds for the wrong reason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can we joyfully and effectively work to be a gospel centered community?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What kind of community is the church supposed to be?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/what-kind-of-community-is-the-church-supposed-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/what-kind-of-community-is-the-church-supposed-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 1:26-2:17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can we act like a biblical gospel centered community?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People generally seek a place of love.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What kind of community are we supposed to be?&#xA;We are called to be &lt;strong&gt;just&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;merciful&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;To not have favoritism.&#xA;You need to bear the burden, do the hard thing. Treat everyone equally.&#xA;How welcoming am I of others?&#xA;We should be encouraged to do the hard thing. Go make the lonely feel less lonely.&#xA;We need to also be merciful as in caring for those in need. Not just being kind, but meeting the needs of others.&#xA;If we are not exercises mercy, or justness, we will be judged by God.&#xA;We need to be merciful because it&amp;rsquo;s the foundation of our faith, God&amp;rsquo;s mercy to us.&#xA;Why is it so hard to achieve?&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not that we don&amp;rsquo;t care for others, but we are inherently fearful of these situations.&#xA;We are really shameful people and don&amp;rsquo;t like to share our struggles. But do we care enough to invest in our community?&#xA;We chase after &lt;strong&gt;human glory&lt;/strong&gt; and not &lt;strong&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s glory&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;The desire to be powerful, rich, social status.&#xA;We favore those that make us feel safe. And we struggle to jepoardize that.&#xA;When we act in favoritism, it shows that we do not understand what God&amp;rsquo;s vision is.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;All people are built in the image of God&amp;rdquo;. No matter who it is, no matter how rude, low iq, low eq, anything. We should not insult ANYONE. We should not make people feel worthless.&#xA;How can we achieve that&#xA;Carefully look upon the glory of Christ. Even if it pains you, even if it&amp;rsquo;s burdensome, you should feel inclined to do good works. To take the harder path.&#xA;Be radical, in the way we speak, act, and love onto others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be a doer not a hearer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/be-a-doer-not-a-hearer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/be-a-doer-not-a-hearer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 1:22-27&#xA;Be doers, not hearers. Anyone who claims to be a christian and has no heart to act upon it, is not a christian. Don&amp;rsquo;t deceive yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any doubt about being a hearer and not a doer, you are simply a hearer. There&amp;rsquo;s no gray area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we look into the bible, we should look intently. Look deeply. Don&amp;rsquo;t glance at the bible as a man would look at himself in a mirror. Instead look as a woman would gaze at herself in the mirror. Look and hear and read and be absorbed into the perfect law.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What DOes It Mean to Live by Faith</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/what-does-it-mean-to-live-by-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/what-does-it-mean-to-live-by-faith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: P.A Speaking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Hebrews 12:1-2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We should inherently be in pursuit of God. We are born to immitate, and we should be immitating that which is perfect, which is God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We usually follow those around us though. It&amp;rsquo;s not wrong to be influenced by others, but we must follow those &lt;strong&gt;worth following.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There should be a goal to reach. Without purpose we cannot find motivation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Though we may feel alone, you must know that we are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I should recieve God&#39;s Word</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/how-i-should-recieve-gods-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/how-i-should-recieve-gods-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&#xA;verse: James 1:19-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;19Â Know this, my beloved brothers: let every personÂ be quick to hear,Â slow to speak,Â slow to anger;Â 20Â for the anger of man does not produce the righteousness of God.Â 21Â ThereforeÂ put away all filthiness and rampant wickedness and receive withÂ meekness the implanted word,Â which is able to save your souls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-does-a-biblical-community-look-like&#34;&gt;What does a biblical community look like?&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graciously acting together. The most important part of christian life is to be a &amp;ldquo;born again believer&amp;rdquo;. A life that is fully influenced by christ. Born against isn&amp;rsquo;t sinless, but toy should have a pursuit of a different kind of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Portrait of Ministry</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/a-portrait-of-ministry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/a-portrait-of-ministry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Mark 6:31-44&#xA;5 Loaves and 2 Fish&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Details we may have missed from this story&#xA;Jesus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sheperd&amp;rsquo;s heart&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always focused on others. Self emptying.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make yourself nothing to serve others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Disciples&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Life Giving Effect of God&#39;s Welcome</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-life-giving-effect-of-gods-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-life-giving-effect-of-gods-welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: An inviting God&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Genesis 2:16-17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Human souls were not made to bear outcomes. We are not in control of the way things turn out. But God does.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Garden of Eden was a place of abundance. This story isn&amp;rsquo; about restriction and limitation and rules. God asks us to care for and maintain this beautiful orchard. We just have to take part of our own responsibilities, and also enjoy the fruit. God invites us to eat until we cant anymore. This center tree is also good but we are just not ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Home?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/what-is-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/what-is-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: An inviting God&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Ephesians 5&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is home? Home is joy comfort rest security etc&#xA;But it can also have conflict bitterness frustration and abuse.&#xA;Everyone desires a home to be filled with joy But is this possible?&#xA;How do people relate to each other? How do we be more christ like?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ must be lord in all your relations. family, lover, employer. in everything. Have Christ be the center of your relationship. Every aspect in life is grounded in Christ. This is a picture of heaven on Earth, and heaven is our home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Rest</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/invited-to-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/invited-to-rest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Matthew 11:25-30&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To know Jesus as the son of God is an invitation to rest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jesus reveals the father to those he chooses?&#xA;He invites weary sinners into his rest.&#xA;Verse 25, Jesus declares himself as the promised Messiah.&#xA;God is easier to understand when you notice all the love he has for us.&#xA;Jesus is unique as he is THE son if God. Jesus transcends.&#xA;A lot of the time we discuss how Jesus is similar to us. He is born in the flesh, suffered, and died. But at the same time he is not like is at all. He is unrelatable, intangible.&#xA;God reveals himself to us and it&amp;rsquo;s a gracious decision. God is dealing with a race of sinners of which he owes nothing.&#xA;Why should we be happy that he hides and reveals. Because he has revealed it to us. We are his little children. Though we are sinful. we were help&#xA;God invites thiose that are tired and burdened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being Imitators of God</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/being-imitators-of-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/being-imitators-of-god/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Ephesians 5:1-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;imitators-of-god&#34;&gt;Imitators of God&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People by nature are imitators&#xA;Donâ€™t imitate the world, imitate God&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;â€œHow can we organically imitate God as Paul urges us to doâ€&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Itâ€™s not just the performance of immoral acts, it must not even be mentioned. Media and culture has normalized these cruel things. To the point we have become desensitized. The result of all these immoralities is a loss of inheritance and Godâ€™s wrath will be upon us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Prayer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-power-of-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-power-of-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: 1 James 5:13-18&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;What does prayer do?&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;the purpose is to bring healing from suffering&#xA;Verse 13: is anyone along you suffering?&#xA;Circumstantial, financial, psycholigcal, spiritual, all types of suffering. And we all experience it&#xA;James says if we suffer, we should pray.&#xA;Also pray when cheerful. Praise God for the glory he deserves. Active, vocal praise because we are joyful.&#xA;Sometimes we may feel too tired or feeble to pray. That&amp;rsquo;s why you need people to pray for you. Try to pray for yourself, but in those moments you can&amp;rsquo;t. Have others do it for you.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s a biblical matter to pray for each other.&#xA;You draw closer to God when you pray. You are restored spiritually. Darkness is lit with the light of Jesus Christ.&#xA;We should also confess our sins to one another. As you do so, pray for one another, it restores broken relationship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being Biblically Blessed</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/being-biblically-blessed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/being-biblically-blessed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Blessed to be a blessing&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: Genesis 12:2-3&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We should focus on the proclamation.&#xA;Blessed to be a blessing is the theme of this year.&#xA;What does it mean to be biblically blessed?&#xA;We have recieved something that we donâ€™t necessarily deserve. (general understanding)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Throughout all of the bible theres a lot of worldly blessings promissed by God. Property, land, freedom, success. But after Jesus comes, you will rarely find these earthly blessings. Youll actually find afflictions and suffering up until Jesusâ€™ ressurection.&#xA;This is to show what it means to be under the blessings and provisions of God.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
