<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pfs on dayowrites</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/pfs/</link><description>Recent content in Pfs on dayowrites</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/pfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Christmas Peace</title><link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/christmas-peace/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/christmas-peace/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Psalm 126&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The true meaning of Christmas is the gift of Jesus Christ and his birth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out greatest gift and dream is the eternal life that the one and only Jesus Christ died to grant. And this dream has &lt;strong>already&lt;/strong> been actualized.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Treasure the Word</title><link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/treasure-the-word/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/treasure-the-word/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Psalm 119
the longest verse in the bible. It&amp;rsquo;s the written account of David and his devout faith.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>People want to make the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; choice for themselves such as &amp;ldquo;what should we eat?&amp;rdquo;. But this created stress in our lives. But what&amp;rsquo;s a decision that we can &lt;strong>never&lt;/strong> forget. It brings joy, peace, stability.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Find delight in the word&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dedictate your life to the word&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Look to the hopeful future and be present in the loment.
Bottom line is to treasure the word of God.
How can you treasure God when yoy don&amp;rsquo;t treasure the word? Treasuring the word, following the commandments, will help you to make the right decisions and run away from sin.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s societal climate makes reading in general, and also specifically the bible, a great struggle. We are so immersed in a culture of instant gratification. I really have to immerse myself in the word of God and absorb and be mindful of it. This is where we should derive our joy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Praying Our Envy</title><link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/praying-our-envy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/praying-our-envy/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Psalm 73&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you happy for others that do well for themselves or are you envious?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The heart of jealousy happens very often.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Don&amp;rsquo;t get caught up in focusing on what you lack. Instead look towards what you do have.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Envy is difficult to self actualize. We do it so often and we can become complacent to the feeling. As we get more discontent with ourselves, we become greedy, self pitying, and hyper critical of oneself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Brokenness to Beauty</title><link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/from-brokenness-to-beauty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/from-brokenness-to-beauty/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Psalm 51
Writer: King David
Context: David was considered a man of God&amp;rsquo;s heart and poweful and wealthy. Considered a very righteous man. But he fell, he commited adultery with a married woman. Nathan a prophet convicts King David about his sin. The story of a rich man and a poor man who had just a single lamb that he cherished very much.
Verse Analysis: The entire verse is a psalm of repentance.
Three pleas:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security in Suffering</title><link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/security-in-suffering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/security-in-suffering/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: Psalm for Suffering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Psalms 16
David calls out to God for refuge because he has been experiencing and dealing with various problems such as being a murderer and adulterer, and also bc of the sins of others such as those that seek to end his life. But note that David isn&amp;rsquo;t asking for an tagimmediate solution. Not a refuge in the sense of freedom of his problems, rather a security amidst danger. A refuge/security that cannot be shaken.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Praying through Fear</title><link>http://localhost:1313/sermons/praying-through-fear/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/sermons/praying-through-fear/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: Psalm for suffering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Psalm 3
Context: David is old and he&amp;rsquo;s being chased by thousands of people. His life is crumbling around him. King David commited adultery and murdered her husband and did a lot of other wrongs.
Fear is not a negative emotion by itself. It can have positive effects.
In 1884, Soren Keurtigard says, &amp;ldquo;fear is the response to a specific identifiable danger or threat&amp;rdquo;. Fear of failure, fear of an angry bear&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>