<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agt on dayowrites</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/agt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agt on dayowrites</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/agt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Call to Prayer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/a-call-to-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/a-call-to-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 5:13-20&#xA;Pray for one another. Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to ask for prayer in times of need.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prayer has the power to change lives. If anyone is suffering in any capacity, let that man pray.&#xA;Are there differences in who prays for us?&#xA;The prayer of a &lt;strong&gt;righteous&lt;/strong&gt; person has a great impact. &amp;ldquo;Is anyone among you sick, so sick that the body the church cannot pray for you. Call for the elders, the leaders of the church, to come pray for you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patience</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/patience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/patience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 5:7-12&#xA;Be patient. Some of you may not be wealthy, maybe suffering, maybe oppressed. But god is exhorting them to be patient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We seek immediate gratification. We are products impatient&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patience -&amp;gt; graciousness and steadiness at the face of delayed gratifications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patience can also mean: Long suffering and remaining steadfast and endure and presevere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not stoicism. It&amp;rsquo;s not about willpower to withstand irritation. It&amp;rsquo;s deeper and more than that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Danger of Wealth</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-danger-of-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-danger-of-wealth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 5:1-6&#xA;Your riches will spoil and your coins will corrode. You kept your own pockets fat at the expense of those that work for you.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Who is James condemning?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;James is addressing to a particular group of people: Christians. He&amp;rsquo;s talking about a majority of people in the church.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The issue is the abuse of wealth. Hoarding it instead of using it for the glory of God. Hoarding is different than saving.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Saving is encouraged by the Bible. It makes good stewards. Hoarding is accumulating so much wealth, more than necessary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Are you trying to accumulate wealth so that you can have control over your life? Trust in God, not in wealth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What are the dangers of wealth?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cure for Worries</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/the-cure-for-worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/the-cure-for-worries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 4:13-17&#xA;Do not be arrogant. Don&amp;rsquo;t boast about tomorrow. Don&amp;rsquo;t talk about doing this or that, just do it. Whatever God wills you to do, just take action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We often become so worried and stressed when things don&amp;rsquo;t go as we plan. How can we deal with this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What causes worries?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forgetting God in our daily lives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Planning without God in mind. The most prevalent and common sin. Whne we forget God in the daily operation of our life, we assume the role of God in ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know whats going to happent tomorrow&amp;rdquo;. This leads to an expectation of a certain reality that may not come true.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;WE DONT KNOW WHAT TOMORROW WILL BRING.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leave it all in the hands of God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When plans go well we feel superior, and when they dont we feel inferior.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the cure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Community of Peace part 2</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 4:1-12&#xA;How to build gospel centered communities.&#xA;Last week we learned we need wisdom, especially to deal with conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We all desire change, to be better.&#xA;We want to be people that are reliable and can make a positive impact.&#xA;You get to experience this change, only when you become a peacemaker. When you live in close community with other christians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem of communities:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Community of Peace</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/a-community-of-peace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 3:13-18&#xA;Peace makes peace&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is wisdom&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fearing the Lord&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;According to verse 13, Wisdom is not just known, but is shown. &amp;ldquo;Let him show his works in the meekness of wisdom.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wisdom is Pure - Morally blameless&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peaceable - people who dislike conflict. Put reconciliation into action. Means to work with others even though it&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gentleness - As you hear good arguments, that you are willing to change. Flexible, yielding to others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Open to reason - Persuadable, a good listener&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Full of mercy - Taking your resources and putting it to use for others in need.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Impartial - Show dignity and respect to all people, because we are all created in the image of God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sincere - Integrity, be wise in public and in private.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We must show these things if you want to be wise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When we are wise, people will come to you, they will be drawn to these characteristics.&#xA;How can we implement it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we don&amp;rsquo;t feel satisfied, we are constantly looking for something to make us feel content.&#xA;Our life feels unsettled and dissatisfied&#xA;This will lead to all kinds of evil and addictions. We find ourseleves doing things we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so that we can be &amp;ldquo;content&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can we have faithful works</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/how-can-we-have-faithful-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/how-can-we-have-faithful-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 2:18-26&#xA;Faith without works is dead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;God calls us to be a community of love. And this can be achieved even with a group of people that share no interest or have similarities. All we need is God.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two pitfalls&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians not doing good works.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christians that do good deeds for the wrong reason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can we joyfully and effectively work to be a gospel centered community?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What kind of community is the church supposed to be?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/what-kind-of-community-is-the-church-supposed-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/what-kind-of-community-is-the-church-supposed-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 1:26-2:17&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can we act like a biblical gospel centered community?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People generally seek a place of love.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What kind of community are we supposed to be?&#xA;We are called to be &lt;strong&gt;just&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;merciful&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;To not have favoritism.&#xA;You need to bear the burden, do the hard thing. Treat everyone equally.&#xA;How welcoming am I of others?&#xA;We should be encouraged to do the hard thing. Go make the lonely feel less lonely.&#xA;We need to also be merciful as in caring for those in need. Not just being kind, but meeting the needs of others.&#xA;If we are not exercises mercy, or justness, we will be judged by God.&#xA;We need to be merciful because it&amp;rsquo;s the foundation of our faith, God&amp;rsquo;s mercy to us.&#xA;Why is it so hard to achieve?&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s not that we don&amp;rsquo;t care for others, but we are inherently fearful of these situations.&#xA;We are really shameful people and don&amp;rsquo;t like to share our struggles. But do we care enough to invest in our community?&#xA;We chase after &lt;strong&gt;human glory&lt;/strong&gt; and not &lt;strong&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s glory&lt;/strong&gt;.&#xA;The desire to be powerful, rich, social status.&#xA;We favore those that make us feel safe. And we struggle to jepoardize that.&#xA;When we act in favoritism, it shows that we do not understand what God&amp;rsquo;s vision is.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;All people are built in the image of God&amp;rdquo;. No matter who it is, no matter how rude, low iq, low eq, anything. We should not insult ANYONE. We should not make people feel worthless.&#xA;How can we achieve that&#xA;Carefully look upon the glory of Christ. Even if it pains you, even if it&amp;rsquo;s burdensome, you should feel inclined to do good works. To take the harder path.&#xA;Be radical, in the way we speak, act, and love onto others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Be a doer not a hearer</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/be-a-doer-not-a-hearer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/be-a-doer-not-a-hearer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;verse: James 1:22-27&#xA;Be doers, not hearers. Anyone who claims to be a christian and has no heart to act upon it, is not a christian. Don&amp;rsquo;t deceive yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any doubt about being a hearer and not a doer, you are simply a hearer. There&amp;rsquo;s no gray area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we look into the bible, we should look intently. Look deeply. Don&amp;rsquo;t glance at the bible as a man would look at himself in a mirror. Instead look as a woman would gaze at herself in the mirror. Look and hear and read and be absorbed into the perfect law.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I should recieve God&#39;s Word</title>
      <link>https://example.org/sermons/how-i-should-recieve-gods-word/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/sermons/how-i-should-recieve-gods-word/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;series: Acting in grace together&#xA;verse: James 1:19-21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;19 Know this, my beloved brothers: let every person be quick to hear, slow to speak, slow to anger; 20 for the anger of man does not produce the righteousness of God. 21 Therefore put away all filthiness and rampant wickedness and receive with meekness the implanted word, which is able to save your souls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;what-does-a-biblical-community-look-like&#34;&gt;What does a biblical community look like?&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graciously acting together. The most important part of christian life is to be a &amp;ldquo;born again believer&amp;rdquo;. A life that is fully influenced by christ. Born against isn&amp;rsquo;t sinless, but toy should have a pursuit of a different kind of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
