<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tgwr on dayowrites</title><link>http://localhost:61827/tags/tgwr/</link><description>Recent content in Tgwr on dayowrites</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:61827/tags/tgwr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Divine Disruption</title><link>http://localhost:61827/sermons/divine-disruption/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:61827/sermons/divine-disruption/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: The God who remembers&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Exodus 3:1-4&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Moses is running away after killing an Egyptian worker for mistreating a Hebrew.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In this set of verses, Moses finds an eternally burning bush.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Note that we can easily consider this a miracle, however it is also not so easily observed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="main-idea">
 Main Idea
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#main-idea">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are moments when we go to God asking for something we desire or feel like we need. But sometimes God answers us by making life more difficult/troublesome. There are often things that we don&amp;rsquo;t realize need to be addressed until God tells us they need to be fixed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seeing as God Sees</title><link>http://localhost:61827/sermons/seeing-as-god-sees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:61827/sermons/seeing-as-god-sees/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: The God who remembers&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Exodus 2:1-10&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The story of Moses&amp;rsquo; birth. His mother hid him in the reeds and the Phaoroh&amp;rsquo;s daughter decides to spare his life. She names him Moses because she, &amp;ldquo;&lt;em>Drew him out of the water&lt;/em>&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Admist a chaos for the Israelites, the mother of Moses sees it differently.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Instead of fearing for her child&amp;rsquo;s life, she instead has a vision similar to God&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the mother deems her son as, &amp;ldquo;Fine&amp;rdquo; or in Hebrew, &amp;ldquo;Tov&amp;rdquo;. Which directly translates to &lt;strong>Good&lt;/strong>. This echos the ideas from Genesis 1, where God found things Good. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t about the child&amp;rsquo;s physical appearance. It was about his &lt;em>character&lt;/em> and she found it good.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Obviously as humans, we have a tendency to react things in a worldly manner. But how much more joyful and at peace could we be if we saw things the way God sees it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where is God in this?</title><link>http://localhost:61827/sermons/where-is-god-in-this/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:61827/sermons/where-is-god-in-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>series: The God who remembers&lt;/p>
&lt;p>verse: Exodus 1:1-22
&amp;ldquo;You won&amp;rsquo;t find any mention of God, miracles, signs, or any amazing parables. Rather hardship, suffering, oppression. But you will see that God is still deeply in work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-is-god-silent-sometimes">
 Why is God silent sometimes?
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#why-is-god-silent-sometimes">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>To give us hope to something &lt;strong>greater&lt;/strong>. Contextually, the Israelites have experienced an absence of God for roughly 400 years. In verse 1, we see the geneological descendants of Abraham in order to show that God is working on the promises he made back in Genesis. God is always there. And he has a masterful plan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>God builds slowly. We see that the people nation of Israel grow to great heights. God has been faithfully helping them multply and grow into a nation. God siliently aided the Israelites.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-god-doing-during-these-lulls">
 What is God doing during these lulls?
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#what-is-god-doing-during-these-lulls">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Silence does not equate to God not working with us. He is always with us and constantly watching over us and working within us. He is always holding our hand. Stand firm and abide in Him.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There will be worldly things that will try to pull you away from trusting in God. They will rip you apart and tear you to pieces. And God &lt;strong>allows these moments too&lt;/strong>. God continues to stay silent but also continues to work. This is because he cares about us and would rather us grow than bring immediate relief. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not punishment, it&amp;rsquo;s preparation for something better&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-should-we-navigate-through-these-quiet-times">
 How should we navigate through these quiet times?
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#how-should-we-navigate-through-these-quiet-times">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Daily faithfulness but what does this look like? Often it&amp;rsquo;ll feel like, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going nowhere. I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough. I&amp;rsquo;m not producing enough. Where are the results?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>